# Omar Oualha

## Software Engineering

Highly seasoned and dedicated IT Professional with all-round technical expertise & an exceptional record of client satisfaction. Adept at facilitating clear and transparent communication between all levels of company staff. Able to work well independently or in coordination with a team. Extensive practical knowledge of complex systems' hardware, software & network.

Detail-oriented |

Organized

**Problem Solver** 

Diplomatic

Creative

Genuinely



## **Personal Details**

Adress: Fitzmauricestraße 10, 50829 Köln, Germany

Email: oualhaomar@gmail.com Phone number: (+49) 178 6992862

Date of birth: 1994-04-28
Website: omaroualha.github.io/



## **Professional Experience**

#### OneFID GmbH | Cologne - Germany

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

March. 2019 - Present

#### Task:

Developing both client and backend component for the 3D foot Scanner, 3D visualization, Server logic, Rest Apis, App Store deployment, CI/CD, Containerization, SCRUM.

Building and Implementing advanced webAssembly solution to compile C++ program on the web browser

#### Technology stack:

 ReactJS - React Native - Expo - Typescript - ExpressJS - WebRTC - OpenCV - three.js - Emscripten - webAssembly (WASM) -Make - I18n - Cypress - Gitlab CI - Docker..

#### OOREDOO | Tunisia

Jan. 2018 - June. 2018

#### System and Networks Administrator

#### Task:

- •Routing Protocols RIP EIGRP OSPF BGP MPLS VRF.
- •Configuration DNS, Active Directory, IDS, OpenVPN.
- •Installation and management of backup tools.
- •Configuration and maintenance of Pfsense Firewalls.

 $\mbox{\bf RESULTS}$  - The establishment of the whole Networking infrastructure.

#### Technology stack:

 Windows Server - Exchange - Vmware - ZABBIX monitoring - Apache - FTP - FileZilla - ZIMBRA(mail) - MongoDB - GNS3 -LINUX.

#### ESPRIT | Tunisia

sep. 2017 – Dec. 2017

#### DEVELOPMENT AND INTEGRATION PROJECT (ACADEMIC PROJECT)

#### Task:

I was involved in all aspects of development, creating a website, mobile application, after the conception of the database for the management of claims and insurance

#### Technology stack:

Java - JavaEE - Spring - SpringBoot - Maven - XHTML - React native - ReactJS

#### FREELANCE | Tunisia

June. 2017 – Aug. 2017

#### **Full Stack Developer**

#### Task:

Conception and development of a Multi-services Forum where you can get the latest news about movies, TV Series and Games. The forum is developed as a web application. We used different technologies for the development of the back end and front end of the application.

#### Technology stack:

• Python - Django - MongoDB - Angular - Javascript - REST API .

ESPRIT | Tunisia Jan. 2017 – May. 2017

#### E-COMMERCE WEB APPLICATION

#### Tack

conception and development of a multiplatform Deals shop. The deals allow people to get the best deals In Tunisia, to get discounts on a variety of goods such as food, clothes, restaurants, cosmetics...

Desktop: Developing an Office Application based on APIs and using the JavaFx graphical library.

**Web:** Creating a web application with the Symfony3 Framework and integration of external bundles (Friends of symfony User(FOS), BBcode ...).

Mobile: Creating a Mobile App with the Code Name One Framework and integration of external services (websocket).

#### Technology stack:

• UML - Java8 - JavaFX - Symfony3 - twig - HTML - CSS - JavaScript - Ajax - JQuerry - CodeName One - SQL - JSON -XML

#### Medianet | Tunisia

Jan. 2016 - Oct. 2016

#### Ful Stack DEVELOPER (GRADUATION PROJECT)

#### Task

Developing both client and server side web application for health & lifestyle. A doctor linkedIN where you can get all information about the nearest doctor or pharmacy to you, Manage doctors and patient appointments.

#### **Technology stack**

· UML - PHP5 - SQL - HTML5 - CSS3 - Javascript - Agil Methodologie - Scrum - Design - Adobe Photoshop - Adobe Illustrator

## Education

#### ESPRIT (The higher institute of engineering and technology)

Sep. 2016 - June. 2019

Field: Software Engineering, ENGINEERING CURRICULUM Result: Extensive Achievement – A+ in the 1st grade

#### The Higher institute of Multimedia Arts "ISAMM" | Tunisia

Sep. 2013 – June. 2016

Field: Computing and Multimedia (Computer Science), Bachelor Degree

Result: Honors: on top of the institution grades



## Languages

ArabicFrench

EnglishDeutsch

NativeFluent - C1.Well - B2

Beginner (A2-level)



## Volunteering / Internships

## Summer Camp, Ukraine

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

### Web Development summer internship

#### DUTIES .

· Designing and implementing a website to manage children's camps holiday requests.

#### Technology stack:

UML – PHP – Wordpress - SQL.

#### AIESEC | MEDINA

2014 - 2016

#### The Vice President in charge Marketing and Communication

#### Task:

- Planning within the Executive Board the projects of the next mandate.
- Manage the team on internal and external communication.
- Manage teams to achieve event success.
- Train Members on Marketing Plan.
- · Prepare reports of the activity.
- Team building to motivate the team.
- Search for sponsors

#### Certifications | AWARDS

2017 - 2018

- Cisco Networking Academy Entrepreneurship
- CCNAroutingandswitching



Programming Languages: javascript | typescript | Java | SQL | PHP | Script Shell | Python

Freamwork: reactJS | React-Native | Expo | Angular | Node.js | ExpressJS | Django | Emscripten | webAssembly | Symfony

CMS: drupal | wordpress

 $\textbf{DataBases:} \ \text{SQL} \ | \ \text{PLSQL} \ | \ \text{NoSQL} \ | \ \text{ORACLE}.$ 

 $\label{eq:continuity} \textbf{Devops:} \ Gitlb \ CI \ | \ pipline \ CI-CD \ | \ Docker \ | \ Kubernetes.$   $\textbf{Environments:} \ Linux \ | \ Windows \ | \ Ubuntu \ | \ OS \ X.$ 

 $\textbf{Modelization:} \ UML(\textbf{U}nified \ \textbf{M}odeling \ \textbf{L}anguage) \mid Scrum \mid Agil$ 

IDE and Software: Adobe PhotoShop | Adobe Illustrator | NetBeans | Eclipse | Apache | Tomcat | PHPStorm | Vs code | GIT GUI |

Sublime Text | Talend | Jboss | Xcode.